<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1D-features on HiCognition</title>
    <link>https://gerlichlab.github.io/hicognition/docs/tags/1d-features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1D-features on HiCognition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 09:56:26 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gerlichlab.github.io/hicognition/docs/tags/1d-features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1D-average</title>
      <link>https://gerlichlab.github.io/hicognition/docs/widgets/lineprofile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 09:56:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerlichlab.github.io/hicognition/docs/widgets/lineprofile/</guid>
      <description>The 1D-average widget can be used to display the average magnitude of a 1D-genomic feature over a specific region set. It is a simple line-profile visualization that can load one or more genomic datasets and implements a simple tooltip that shows the magnitude of the specific data sets.
Suitable data The 1D-average widget is suitable for any genomic dataset that can be represented using a bigwig file. This includes coverage tracks for Chip-seq experiments, Gro-seq experiments, and features derived from Hi-C data, such as insulation scores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacked lineprofiles</title>
      <link>https://gerlichlab.github.io/hicognition/docs/widgets/stackup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 09:56:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerlichlab.github.io/hicognition/docs/widgets/stackup/</guid>
      <description>The stacked line profile widget can be used to display individual examples of 1D-genomic features over a specific region set. It is a heatmap representation, where each row corresponds to one genomic region.
The stacked line profile widget does not show the entirety of the selected region-set, but only a subset. The down-sampling ratio can be defined as configuration variable (see the configuration section for details)
 Suitable data The stacked line profile widget is suitable for any genomic dataset that can be represented using a bigwig file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1D-feature embedding</title>
      <link>https://gerlichlab.github.io/hicognition/docs/widgets/1d_feature_embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 09:56:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerlichlab.github.io/hicognition/docs/widgets/1d_feature_embedding/</guid>
      <description>The 1D-feature embedding widget can be used to display the distribution of genomic regions with regards to a collection (see here for more details on collections) of 1D features. It represents a 2-dimensional embedding of the genomic regions as a heatmap of points.
Suitable data The 1D-feature embedding widget is suitable for a collection of 1D features. 1D-features are any genomic dataset that can be represented using a bigwig file. This includes coverage tracks for Chip-seq experiments, Gro-seq experiments, but also features derived from Hi-C data such as insulation scores.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>